# **CONNOR LEWIS-SMITH**

# **Quantitative Social Scientist**

+1 (206) 948-8360

connorlewissmith@gmail.com

Seattle, WA

www.linkedin.com/in/connorlewissmith/ connorlewissmith.github.io/

# SUMMARY

Currently studying fishing community characteristics and developing social vulnerability index measures to inform management decisions as a Data Management Specialist with the Pacific States Marine Fisheries Commission in support of NOAA Fisheries Conservation Biology at the Northwest Fisheries Science Center.

#### **EXPERIENCE**

# **Data Management Specialist**

**Pacific States Marine Fisheries Commission** 5/2022 - current

- Developed, maintained, and distributed information from relational databases concerning fishing communities to contribute to the California Current Ecosystems Assessment and Coastal Community Snapshots in support of the NOAA Fisheries Conservation Biology Office.
- Overseeing the creation of social indicator measures for West Coast recreational fishing communities.
- · Researching fishing community risk mitigation with data from the NOAA West Coast Fishery Participation surveys while coordinating survey design and deployment.

# **Graduate Research Assistant**

**University of Washington** 6/2021 - 8/2022

- Generated high quality summaries, figures, statistical reports, and static maps for a range of customized data on topics ranging from domoic acid, fisheries landings, fisheries participation survey responses, and fish barrier inventories.
- Compiled and organized spatial datasets from diverse sources to produce a qualitative comparison of fish barrier prioritization indexes.
- Produced an online interactive map application for the public to view survey results aggregated to broad spatial scales.

# Trip Leader and Manager/Operations Expert **Backroads**

- 6/2016 7/2020
- High performance led to promotions from trip prep specialist to trip leader, to regional manager/operations expert of the Southwestern United States
- Developed expertise in environmental and social issues in over 8 regions to educate clients
- Authored global information packets as part of a writing team

# **EDUCATION**

#### **Masters of Marine Affairs**

University of Washington, School of Marine and **Environmental Affairs** 2020 - 2022

#### **Graduate Certificate in Climate Science**

University of Washington, Program on Climate Change 2020 - 2022

# **Bachelor of Arts: Biology**

**Occidental College, Los Angeles** 2012 - 2016

#### Semester Abroad

American University of Sharjah, UAE 2015

### PROGRAMMING SKILLS

Proficient/Advanced:

R and Git

Intermediate:

Python, HTML, CSS, BASH, SQL, Docker, Google Cloud Platform

# **PRESENTATIONS**

North American Association of Fisheries Economists Meeting, Drivers of Health Insurance Status in the West Coast Commercial Fishing Fleet, May 2023.

# **PUBLICATIONS**

Lewis-Smith, C., Jardine, S., Holland, D., & Norman, K. In press. Drivers of Health Insurance Status in the West Coast Commercial Fishing Fleet. Marine Resource Economics.

Harvey, Chris, Andy Leising, Nick Tolimieri, and Greg Williams. n.d. "2022-2023 CALIFORNIA CURRENT **ECOSYSTEM STATUS REPORT."** 

# **AWARDS**

Jay Ginter Memorial Scholarship Fund, University of Washington, 2021